Catrat is the most common cause of treatable blindness globally.
It is important to be able to examine a patient and confirm the cause of treatable catrat.
Start by asking if the cyclose has been gradual or sudden.
If one or both eyes are affected, and if there has been any pain or readiness.
Next, test visual acuity for distance and in A.
Use a pinhole to make sure the lack of glasses are not the cause.
Then look at the pupils.
Are they black, round and equal?
Do they react to light?
If you have a bright light, check if the pupil constricts.
In advanced cataract, the pupil can look white.
Even in cataract, the pupil should still react to light.
Examine the front of the eye more closely with an acolyte or with some device.
Check to make sure nothing else is wrong with the eye, especially a cornea scar.
With an acolyte, you can also check for the yellow or reindefundal reflex.
In an eye with cataract, there can be dark spots.
Patches missing or be completely absent, looking
dark or even white in mature cataracts.
If the vision is poor and the fanroly flex looks okay, then there may
be other reasons
for loss of vision.
This is especially the case if the pupil does not constrict well to light.
Examination of the back of the eye will help wake out what is wrong.
There may be a problem with the optic nerve or retina or both.
The nerve may have a large gap due to glaucoma or be paired from
loss of blood supply, compression
or lack of food.
The retina may be damaged by diabetes, scarred by infection or may be detached.
In this case, cardiac surgery may not improve the vision.
In summary, when assessing for cataract, take a history, test visiography, look at the
front of the eye to confirm cataract and exclude other diseases.
Look to see if the bipus are round, black, symmetrical and reactive to light, and if
able to perform a fondle reflux test and examine the back of the eye.